Uh good afternoon everyone. Very excited
to be here to be talking about the post
training verified by agents. So the
agent AI course is a super exciting
course. uh believe that you'll be able
to learn a lot from lots of uh uh people
and first of all that disclaimer that
everything I talk about here in the
lecture all the views I express are
solely those of the guest is me and not
represented
representative of the company including
Nvidia or or UC Berkeley.
So we'll be focusing on post training
variable agents which is a very
important topics in building highly
reliable agent systems uh from the basic
requirements of building agentic models.
So how do the agentic models different
uh differ from traditional large
language models? From the very early
days when was first produced
uh we use a technique called reinforced
learning from human feedback. At that
time the language models really train to
align really well with human preference.
For example, they interact with you.
They really understand what you are
saying, make you feel better.
But later essentially all the uh
frontier labs and all the model vendors
started to add this agentic capabilities
to their models and precisely for
agentic model the model is really
aligned with the environment feedbacks.
uh by environment I actually mean
something very specific later I will
detail they are designed to provide
interactions that to maximize verifiable
rewards in addition to human preference.
So basically when you actually talking
to those agency language models they are
supposed to really understand your
intentions very well because it's uh
designed to first maximize human
preference but also at the same time
it's designed to help you accomplish
tasks. That's extremely critical and for
evaluating the quality of task
completion we usually use something
different from generic reward models
because for certain task maybe there
will be a few correct answers and there
will be really wrong answers. You
absolutely cannot do that and usually
for human preference uh the situation is
slightly different.
So brief recap of earlier models that
were trained to be great chat bots. The
way we treat usually is the following.
Say you collect lots of human assistant
chats. Human says something, assistant
says something. Then later you would
like to rank assistant responses based
on human preference. Maybe you uh uh do
sourcing, ask lots of people. Uh then
you collect this human preference. Then
you try to figure out the reward
modeling technique to come up with a
reward model basically based on the
human assistant interactions trying to
create whether a certain response from
the assistant is good or not. Once you
get really high quality reward model we
like to start training the language
model so that it can actually behave
better in terms of maximizing human
preference. There are many algorithm you
can use here. So I also includes SFT.
Sometime people say SFT which is
abbreviation for superstine tuning is
mostly used for strictly mim mimicking
the expert behavior. I include here
because SFT actually is also being used
a lot even when you are given a reward
model. So the intuition is that uh I can
use a reward model to create multiple
different responses from the assistant.
Then basically I can only choose those
assistant responses that rank very high
by the reward model then conduct super
fine tuning on those responses. I can
also use other reinforcement learning
algorithms like PO and GRPO any
algorithm you come up with or you have
heard of finally to produce a model to
maximize human preference. Hopefully by
talking to that model you feel that it's
really engaging model really understands
you. You feel very happy about this.
Feel free to also stop me when you have
questions.
Uh what more is necessary? So turns out
one of the key applications of IM is
actually agency tasks conversations is
not verifiable. There are also usually
no clear single correct answer. You use
a really sophisticated reward model to
model preference and records interaction
with the user only. uh but in terms of
enterprise applications of LMS many
tasks they have a uh they actually
require the deep interaction between the
human sometimes multiple people multiple
assistants and many other entities uh
including the environments uh specific
code repo specific software system and
many different tools. So basically you
need to make sure that IM is able to
understand the feedback given by many
different entities understand the full
states uh of this environment and also
make sure that when I am perform a
certain task uh it's able to really
produce the correct answer and there's a
very clear verifier demonstrating
whether the answer is correct or not and
you should really not produce the wrong
answers because that's going to make the
whole system totally crash. Uh so
sometimes people say that you can use
other detistic system to help fix that
but one thing people have found is that
if the IM is not strong enough in
producing essentially right answers uh
it's very very hard to build a reliable
system even after you do lots of
software engineering on top of this.
So precisely uh for today's models they
are trained to be great agents. Uh the
user no longer ask a question saying how
are you? Uh you start very engaging
conversations. your user has a very
clear target sometimes even wake but
there's something user wants to
accomplish they I want to achieve this I
want to book flights I want to talk to
my server system then I am needs to be
able to understand this and precisely uh
execute so there are many different ways
to evaluate the outputs of and the
system uh there are different rubrics
divide by people uh uh you can also
write down different ground truths uh
you have a very clear recording of the
environmental states and you also
conduct lots of unit tests to check the
output of thems by doing this you get a
very good signals you understand whether
the output in this case is right or not
then you start to use lots of other post
training algorithms again super fine
tuning uh po gpo uh to actually uh uh
improve the model so eventually the goal
is that you want to construct a very
strong agentic model to maximize
correctness by interacting with with uh
uh waiting sandboxes with very complex
tools. I will try to make everything
very precise later when we go into the
details of this.
Okay.
Uh but what is needed to train the
verifiable agent models in particular?
It is a very important topic lots of
people in the community are focusing on.
I would say that there are three core
steps and each one is actually very
challenging these days. It really
requires the collaboration of many
people across industry across academia
to contribute to this so that we'll be
able to get a very very strong agency
language models in the future. So the
first step I say to get good uh
verifiable training data to train agents
without high quality training data we
simply cannot produce very high quality
agent LMS. I be talking about the
challenges behind getting very high
quality training data. The step two is
actually evaluation.
You collect the data, you figure out
your training uh uh uh approach, you
train the model, but then you need to
really understand whether it's good or
not. So generally there's a very
dangerous trend of really uh entering
the in this uh illusion that we feel we
collect the data, the data is
comprehensive enough, then we only test
the things that are really aligned with
our data. It really appears that
everything's working really well. Then
suddenly we test everything in a while
things start to break. So how do we
define a verifiable agents? We actually
talking about uh some concrete examples.
Uh maybe let's try to make it even more
concrete. For example, one thing could
be that uh you're solving a math
problem. Then uh the computer also has
access to certain tools. For example,
Python coding tool. Then after accessing
to the coding tool, writing lots of
codes, understanding a problem, finally
the IM is supposed to produce an answer.
For example, the final answer to the
math problem is number two. Then I want
to make sure it's uh precisely uh uh the
right answer. So in just one example,
the other examples in software
engineering, you're able to produce a
code a code script and then there are
many different ways to check the
validity of the code. For example, there
are so many different unit tests I can
write. You need to be be able to pass
all of these tests to make sure that's
finally is correct. Uh turns out it is
really complicated question. So there
are so many different verifiers you can
build and the current challenge
everybody is facing in the community is
that we haven't got enough uh strong
verifiers to really make sure that we
capture all the all the corner cases of
the intelligence.
So uh the third step uh is actually also
about training. So this is also a very
uh uh complex topics until today many
people community are trained very hard
to research on this which is that I got
very good training data. I also figure
out how do we evaluate my agents. But
what exactly is the best way of feeding
the data to the model so that the models
intelligence in fact actually improves
u in some sense when we think about
building the verifiable agents we really
think about this essentially as training
a human being. So when you're training
uh like engineer in a company what
usually you do is that you first gave
some instructions you say well maybe
you're supposed to write code in this
way or you're supposed to operate the
software system in certain way then the
person started doing that started
writing code started interacting with
the software system submitting tickets
things like that then sometimes they
will make mistakes but they will receive
some feedback.
Uh the key challenge is that uh for a
human you can just tell the human well
here's a feedback I give to you. What
about next time you do better but for
the machine the hardest part is to
transform this natural human interaction
into something that's implementable by
algorithm. So the algorithm needs to
make sure once the per first attempt
something but it made a mistake. I give
the very detailed feedback. How do I
guarantee the next time the also
attempts the same question? The quality
of his time actually improves. If I'm
not able to achieve this, then basically
I'm not able to replicate this natural
feedback loop of human learning. Then
we're going to really hit a plateau of
the final intelligence of the system. So
that's why the step three is also
extremely critical. We'll also be
spending lots of time talking about step
three including some approaches people
have taken in the past. But I really
want to emphasize that uh all all the
three steps they require very extensive
research at this point. So it's actually
a fascinating opportunity to for
everyone to get into the field at this
point.
Okay, talking about the first thing
getting good training data.
So uh agentic models maximize verifiable
rewards. uh what exactly would be the uh
core components of training data that uh
uh we specify to really make sure that
they actually of high quality. So I
first of want to emphasize three
different things they are kind of very
very related in certain literature maybe
they are combined together but I do
think that uh I think that things are
are slightly different. So I want to
emphasize uh three different aspects of
the data sets. The first is called the
environment. So how do I think about the
environment for the agent? So say you
build a a coding agent, right? So
basically the agent uh takes in your
instructions trying to generate code in
a well formulated the code ripple. Maybe
the code repo has some issues. There's
certain bugs. You're supposed to fix
that. Then the environment basically
encodes the the whole state of this
ripple. For example, the prefix and
surfig of the code script and lots of
files we have loaded, lots of downstream
task we need to deal with. Uh they
describe the the states of the
environment and also it includes lots of
system prompts people have already set
up for different parts to work together.
The second part I want to talk about uh
is tools. So basically uh the agentic
IMS they are trained to generate tokens
that have consumed by software tools to
provide additional relative information
to the model. So precisely you should
think of this as additional in software
engineering language additional APIs
provided uh to the system. For example,
you call the system. Well, if the user
ask you a question, what's the today's
weather? IM is not supposed to know
that, but AM really knows that it is
access to certain APIs that's able to
access to this weather. The IM is
supposed to be producing the exact API
call uh to the external system. Then
external system should be able to
feedback the concrete information
regarding to this weather. AM should be
able to internalize that. then finally
uh presents the final answer to the
user. So it could the APIs could it
could provide additional information.
The APIs could actually also help change
the environment state. So basically your
working environments the state is really
complex has lots of different moving
parts. Then maybe you are given certain
tools to help you modify the states
because maybe in order to actually
accomplish certain task there will be
certain states that needs to be changed.
Maybe even the user doesn't doesn't know
that. But as a very strong agent I am
the uh the assistant is supposed to know
that user gives a task then the agent is
supposed to be able to decompose the
task figure out what exactly are the
right tools to call change the
environmental states if necessary uh and
finally produce the answer and the point
story is really about checking the
answer. So basically model are trained
to generate tokens it produce the answer
but how do we even know if the answer is
correct or not? We need to build the
so-called verifiers. The verifiers will
tell you whether you have really
succeeded in combinational tasks. In
some sense, it's also quite challenging
because there are lots of intricate
issues related to evaluation. Maybe you
really produced a right answer but you
took it took you like so many steps. It
consumed so many tokens. Maybe I'm our
access also supposed to penalize you to
this. So even for that turns out it's
really very good to think about
verifiers not as a single number
checking it is correct or not think of
this really as a vector talking about uh
evaluating the quality of the model from
many different perspectives. It can be
unit test for code we just talk about
math checker for proofs or for web
tasks. You can also check whether you
have really accomplished certain task on
your browser.
So the three aspects
uh then I want to talk about some of the
challenges in preparing the the data. So
the first step is to get good training
data in getting in training this very
strong agentic
and in order to really make sure it
works in the wild it appears that you
need to really follow a principle to say
I need to understand many different
environments. I need to have a system
that's able to use many different kinds
of tools. I also need to make sure the
system does well on so many different
verifiers that actually is very
interesting and it's also the lessons
learned by the whole community over the
past uh uh uh two years uh showing that
um one definitely shouldn't be uh uh
tricked to believe that the whole system
is working very well when you actually
only working with very few environments
very limited verification because uh the
system would indeed break once you go
beyond the the the scope of your data
and the key challenge here is really
make sure that you got enough coverage.
So here I want to give you some some
more examples talking about. So what we
have been um um discussing on high level
say you want to train a very strong
agentic system and then there are so
many possible combinations of
environments tools and verifiers. For
example, in environments, there can be
math. Uh for uh math environments, you
are given a problem, then interact with
the user and the provides answer, then
you could have a math verify verifiers
uh proof checker uh then in the
environments you actually could also
have access to different coding tools.
That's why these days sometimes when you
use chatgbtd you see that you ask a math
question charge GBT actually would call
uh u python uh try to write some script
to really verify that answer is actually
correct uh or you are working with
enterprise software for example here I
talk about the sales assistant then it
to access different software API tools
maybe a sales person wants to ask
today's weather I want to get news maybe
I also want to access a database built
in my system maybe I I want understand
who actually are my customers, what
exactly uh is the progress uh with
customers and maybe I I want to really
uh write really a precise query language
to query the database and also to make
sure that I'm able to internalize the
outputs from the database.
So many different types of environments
uh tools and verifiers is very
important. we we achieve very good
coverage and it's always an interesting
challenge to make sure that we have
indeed covered the uh all the important
aspects we care about. Uh so that's why
it's also super exciting time to do
research because uh always uh uh we got
something more to work on.
uh one thing I want to really emphasize
uh which uh uh is is a very fair quality
and these days when we look at the open
source community is actually one thing
that's uh uh that's really lacking at
this point. Uh so generally
one thing one have uh one has observed
is that it's very easy to think about
one rule to verify a certain answer and
just put it down as a single verifier.
But uh the thesis that has appeared
again again in the community was that
whenever we thought we have built a very
high quality verifier in checking the
answer of the LMS turns out we have
missed some corner cases. So here I'm
just showing you something very basic
which has already been covered by the
community but there are way more complex
examples showing that it's actually
quite difficult. For example, let's say
uh the user has a question. I want to
ask how much change would I get back if
I buy a drink for 50 cents and give a
dollar. Then I'm give a multiple
different answers. Right? So basically
can give uh uh one half two or four.
Then in terms of the verify quality you
are really supposed to say that all of
these are correct because they actually
indeed uh uh tell you what's the right
amount of change. However, uh users
question could actually also include
something uh more stringent. For
example, uh in addition to just asking
you how much change would I get back, I
have additional request. Please just
give me the simplest form. So once I
have that verifier answer is supposed to
be different uh because supposed to be
uh one half then in these cases uh in
particular it's very easy to make
mistakes when you are constructing
verifiers and those those cases are
usually very costly because generally
these days are already quite strong.
You'll give them a very simple question,
it will able to answer it and only in
those challenging cases would they
sometimes make a mistake but if you
verify it's also wrong didn't capture
the nuance uh in the in the question you
you absolutely cannot further improve
the quality of the so that's actually
one thing we really want to emphasize
is uh false positive or false negative
which is better or worse maybe more more
significant
uh actually in our experiences I would
say that it's it's very important to
minimize both types of errors
uh because it's u sometimes of course
it's also because uh in uh in different
applications you assign different
weights to different types of arrows but
in reality
uh you can always find the interesting
applications where uh a particular type
of arrow either false positive or false
negative could
uh produce catastrophic results. So you
really want to make sure that doesn't
really happen. You want to conduct
minimal software engineering to finally
fix the the outputs of thems.
So I'm just showing this as example
trying to convince you it's actually
quite challenging to write very good
verifiers because there are lots of
nuance uh in evaluating the final
output.
Okay. So then we we talk about the first
part which is uh how to get a very high
quality training data uh in order to
train a very high uh very very good
agency.
Now then we talking about the second
comp uh component which is getting good
evaluation data. So it's kind of
connected to training data. uh but uh in
reality we focus on this we do try to uh
view this from different perspective in
some sense even trying to tackle certain
aspects that are not really being paid
attention to in training because the
intuition is that uh uh we really want
the training to be generalizable. So
basically in collecting training data
there's actually no way we have
collected all the data in the world. For
example, just think about amount of data
human being would produce when we are
interacting with internet when we are
internet interacting with a browser or
when we are doing math proofs or
engineers code that's basically
unlimited there actually is no way we
just cover all of them. So the whole
point is that you want to build a very
good pipeline to make sure that once you
achieve solid coverage of training data,
it's supposed to generalize to many
environments you haven't really seen
because there's absolutely no way you
you see uh all of these the different
environments. That's actually one task
that this good evaluations uh is
supposed to capture. For example, here
I'm just listing very few uh uh uh like
targets of a good aentic model. Later
I'll be talking about some existing
evaluation systems people have already
built to capture those targets. For
example, one thing uh I want agents to
work with many different tools. It's so
natural if agent can only work with a
few different tools. I give a new one,
maybe the user modifies a tool, then the
system just breaks. We really cannot
tolerate that. It's also expected to
work for many different use cases. It's
also very natural because maybe the user
today also uh uh comes up with a
different use case. You also do not want
the system to break. It operates with
software assistant one but there's so
system two with slightly motivated API.
you want this to continue to work
and you also another core aspect in in
particular uh in the human interactions
I think it's also being surfaced again
and again is that agents are expected to
work under vaguely specified
instructions so in the very early days
of agentic systems when people are
designing evaluation is always like the
user would have a very clear target the
user would say please conduct this then
you see that IM behaves very
intelligently it's really to able to
decompose the problem, execute the task,
calling the APIs in the right way. But
later in reality, people really found in
the wild when people started to interact
with those agents, they have absolutely
no idea they want what they want to do.
So basically asking random questions,
they actually hoping the agent could
tell them what they should do to in
order to accomplish this task. So in
some sense really means that you need a
very smart system. The system should be
able to understand human intentions by
proactively talking to people but also
at the same time produce very precisely
formatted uh uh uh outputs so that they
can actually interact with very rigid uh
rigidly formatted software systems. So
number four agents expect to work under
many different software systems. For
example you use cursor in programming I
build a system for cursor works very
well. Suddenly you change to another
system I use exact same completely
breaks. Uh it's definitely not ideal and
if that really happens and also brings
people into question the the quality and
the intelligence of your of your large
language model because maybe it just
simply isn't smart enough to understand
those changes. This generally will be
very problematic. Uh the fifth one is uh
very generic. I call here expected to be
robust. is really because there are so
many things could actually go wrong in
interaction with humans and with
software systems. Human beings may not
really know what they want and the solar
system could also sometimes produce
issues. You want to make sure that the
really behaves as a really smart person
uh just like uh very high quality
engineers who be able to debug all
different issues that emerge in our
daily life.
So uh the slides will be also be made
available online. Uh here I just want to
give you some more concrete examples of
what people have already done in the
past. So uh those benchmarks uh they
actually they do map uh to the specific
requirements we have been talking about
here. For example uh one two is about
different tools and different use cases.
Uh so on the left I'm showing the
offtheshelf benchmarks which actually
cover many different use cases, many
different tools and there's also uh
number four on the different server
systems. So here uh I'm I'm I'm talking
about different agent harnesses uh which
I will also uh describe in detail and
number 35 here is focusing on unit test
evaluations checking robustness of the
of the outputs. Okay, so maybe uh I'll
start from the left. So uh in the past
uh a couple of years uh the community
has developed uh some really significant
benchmarks trying to push the
intelligence higher and higher. The
benchmarks getting harder and harder.
Generally the people have achieved a
tremendous uh progress and uh indeed per
our observations certain task that in
the past were believed to be very hard
forms these days they can actually solve
them. uh turns out they really produce a
very significant productivity king here
I'm talking about a couple of them for
example sweet bench really uh is really
challenging the to really solve this um
uh very very sophisticated github issues
many times really needs to involve so
many different tools to solve these
issues and also through solving sweet
bench also many people understand that
you're actually supposed to be
interacting with different harnesses I
want to really emphasize is because
there's a very complex like GitHub issue
you need to solve but to solve it many
people actually operating in different
environments for example in one
environments maybe you have a function
called open this file you can you are
supposed to just call this function to
open the file maybe in another
environment you ex you do you do not
have this function you have some other
command line tools you call to actually
accomplish the same task so the whole
point is that in order to check your
capability is solving three venge you're
actually not supposed to be only
sticking to a particular harness you're
supposed to be trying so many different
ones showing that for this particular
task maybe when I give you this set of
different tools another set of different
tools slightly different formulas of
tools are you able to solve it in all
circumstances
if you can it really means that your
intelligence has already achieved a
certain threshold
uh that's actually extremely important
points uh there also are different other
benchmarks like towel bench, BFCL also
from Berkeley uh complex function bench
covering a very wide variety of
different tools, different application
scenarios just to make sure that you do
not overfeit to a particular
application. And there also different
unit test evaluations. For example,
those actually could be uh will be the
focus of uh many uh community members
from a long time ago saying that I want
to check the structured output adherence
which means that maybe in many cases I
want you to produce a JSON output. Uh I
really want to make sure it's it's
really exactly right JSON. So I want to
make sure you do not really need me to
later write a very complex software
engineering code to correct the mistakes
produced by IM. There has been lots of
attempts in the past to produce such
software engineering tools somehow to uh
reduce the burden on IM but later
essentially what everybody observed is
that if the IM itself is not intelligent
enough is not able to produce very high
quality JSON or structured outputs it
becomes essentially impossible for for
anyone to fix the issues later because a
lot of issues really involve very nuance
understanding of the system and it
really requires system with very high
level intelligence. So basically you
cannot easily fix it using very simple
rules.
So one point uh to summarize what they
talk about which is a holistic
environments we want to make sure we
check all kinds of capabilities
humanities last exam uh general uh
scientific knowledge am math sweet bench
encoding it's supposed to be combined
with different harnesses and I want to
make sure that we really create uh super
strong super intelligent model that's
able to solve all of these tasks under
all kinds of combinations of evaluations
to convince ourselves that indeed we
have made progress in terms of
enhancements of intelligence. So keeping
the definition of intelligence holistic
is extremely important because uh uh
these days we are trying to utilize the
systems to increase our productivity and
one thing uh has come up again and again
is that uh uh the system we are dealing
with in practice as a scientist as
engineer as a researcher it's just so
complicated. So in order to make sure
the systems can actually help us, we
want to make sure it is smart enough.
Okay. So uh to continue what we talk
about good evaluations need to count for
all of these things. Evaluate many
different tasks and verifiers many
different ways of letting the agent
explore in a benchmark sandbox by seeing
how the accuracy changes as you swap out
the harnesses. You make sure that if you
see sometimes a very significant
performance drop maybe means that you
did something wrong in the in training
then you need to figure out new ways of
training to to fix this. You also need
to deal with many different tools how to
use different tools in different action
spaces and ideally you really stick to
the same model. So that model needs to
itself figure out what to do. So in
summary evaluation is extremely
important. Lots of people here also
working on very uh significant topics in
evaluation. It is definitely something
we need a help uh uh from from the whole
community on because only by
collectively working on this can we
really understand the limitations of
existing agentic system and make
progress. So it really needs to be
holistic and good measure.
uh one last thing I want to talk about
uh before we go into the training aspect
is actually also about uh uh maybe
approaches to combine different task and
the harnesses to evaluate. So basically
uh say you have already come up with
lots of different evaluations right for
example checking the quality of math
quality of code swapping the harnesses
making sure things are actually good uh
well then you saw some good numbers. So
are you are you still really sure that
you didn't really overfeit all these
benchmarks because maybe in this process
of iterating on your post training you
have collect some data which is really
similar to some of the data in your
evaluation or in the whole community
maybe uh certain models have already
been contaminated maybe certain
evaluations should no longer really work
are you really sure it's not happening
when you see a high number on certain
benchmark say on SWE bench are you
really sure you are it's very strong. Uh
so uh I would like to emphasize that uh
there's also a very important community
effort to continuously trying to check
the quality of evaluations uh which is
also important aspects of AM research.
So basically several aspects one could
consider one thing is about hardness. So
basically suppose at the very early days
maybe IM are not intelligent enough
there will be certain benchmarks maybe
all the IM would score very low on this
benchmarks but maybe these days for
example like GSM 8K everyone scores very
high on this benchmark now you say well
I achieved a five point improvement on
this benchmark it's really unclear you
have actually made some progress because
it's also maybe likely for the specific
base model you work on the model has
already been exposed to certain data.
That's very similar to a GSMK
evaluation. You really do not know
what's going on. You need to
continuously monitor hardness. You also
need to continuously monitor
separability. By that, I mean that when
you ask a question and you ask many
differents the same question.
Ideally, you are supposed to see that
that's supposed to be stronger, they
answer the question better. The IM
that's supposed to be weaker, they they
do not answer as well. In that case, we
would like to say that the benchmark is
able to separate the capabilities of RMS
because if that doesn't really happen or
you observe that well the weaks and
strongs they produce very similar scores
maybe the reaction should be that you
abandon this benchmark because there
must be something that has gone wrong in
the in the past either in training or in
some other types of evaluation that has
maybe has hurt the credibility of this
particular benchmark. There's also of
course issue of diversity which is also
the uh the topic we have been talking
about again and again which is that you
need to have very good coverage. So if
you do not have very good coverage you
you produce high number maybe uh on data
sets you only have like 50 different
prompts they all very similar to each
other uh you produce a high score
doesn't really mean that your system
actually is behaving very well. So all
these are very important topics uh and
it's really a very significant community
effort to make sure that we uh do not
fall into the the pitfalls.
Uh
there so many benchmarks are really is
public. So all the data is available. Uh
are there attempts people have to create
the private benchmarks to really track
the progress? Clearly there are so
actually lots of uh uh individuals,
community members and companies they
would like to create the private
benchmarks to really check that. Um so
in some sense maybe the uh uh the
situation everyone wants to see will be
that uh we need to see way more
benchmarks being proposed because
private benchmark is good but if you
have a very static benchmark then people
try to fit it so many times uh maybe
still would lose credibility and ideally
uh let's say for public benchmarks if
the community can continue to produce
more and more benchmarks in all kinds of
different environments
then it's actually very hard for
everyone to overfeed to all of them.
Then there was a saying that well
suppose you have only five benchmarks in
the world. Uh you have a benchmax them.
So basically you claim your model is
really the best on the five. Uh maybe it
may not really work on all other
benchmarks. But if the community has
collectively produced one billion
benchmarks, right, covering essentially
everything we do in reality, math,
coding, computer use, whatever, then say
that someone comes up and say that I
have over fits to all be one billion
benchmarks, then maybe you have already
achieved AGI because they they really
have already covered everything that uh
uh you care about. So in some sense
benchmarking efforts uh uh is really a
very strong community effort. So we
really would only be able to succeed
when more and more people are producing
very high quality benchmarks covering
their use cases. Uh so that's actually
also an aspect uh I personally feel that
academia can really make a very strong
contribution to uh because um uh there
are many people working on so many
different topics. So uh trying to uh
really capture uh what is actually
missing in the existing training of the
agentic systems.
Great. Then we'll be talking about uh uh
the third part training. Well
uh what does the training agent mean? So
training is a very complex topic these
days. We still have new algorithms
coming up every day. Um but generally I
want to talk about the principle of
training. So in terms of training, you
want the agents to attempt the different
actions in your specific environment and
see what gets it to the final answer the
best. Whichever gets you the best
results, you want the model to reinforce
and repeat. So here I'm talking about
this paradigm. See that on the left
there's a which is supposed to be smart.
Okay, you are training the agents.
So you give the agent a certain task.
You say well please accomplish certain
task try to do it then I would make lots
of attempts attempt here I'm showing one
to five go to environments maybe each
attempt it tries to call different tools
uh try to ch different information try
to make a final decision then finally
there's a verifier saying oh uh for each
attempt is correct or not correct how
much cost has it incurred
uh then ideally uh even without
demonstrating How we train this? We
already know the the target. The target
will be that I want to make sure at the
very end after training the AM is able
to generate uh the correct trajectory.
So the attemp is successful maybe
ideally also with the minimal cost and
there could also be other aspects I care
about in final evaluation.
So what what are some aspect some core
characteristic you you focus on in the
whole training process? I'm talking
about two here. There could be many
others. One thing I want to emphasize
that you want each attempt to be very
different from each other. Since you
want a model to reinforce or discourage
many different styles of attempts just
like a human being, right? Suppose I
want to teach a kid to do something.
Then ideally uh if the person is able to
come up with multiple different
approaches, they're very different from
each other. Then ideally some of them is
correct, some of them is incorrect.
After I give very detailed feedback, I
hope the person can learn very fast. But
the issue is that if the person is only
able to come up with a single answer and
it's wrong, then by telling the person
it is wrong, uh it did give some
information and then it really appears
that it's slightly harder for actually
for the training algorithm to work.
Appears that you didn't provide enough
amount of information at least for for
many algorithms to be able to improve
the quality of agentic systems.
And a second aspect I also want to
emphasize is that every attempt uh would
cause compute to sample and process. You
ask I am as a person to say oh what
about you try this they tried it and
it's totally wrong. You ask to try 100
times all of them are totally wrong.
That wouldn't be very satisfactory
because each attempt cost lots of money
lots of resources. You do not want very
silly attempts. So somehow we are really
in a dedicated situation. So if we give
IM a question it's super easy all the
attempts are exactly correct. It didn't
learn anything. But ask to attempt many
times with all failures cost lots of
money resources
uh and you also need to spend lots of
time figuring out how to make learn. So
it's a really complicated process. till
today uh I believe the whole community
is still trying to figure out what's the
right way to deal with this but I think
that by connecting this better with the
human learning process I did raise lots
of really fascinating questions about
that
so uh we want to talk about some of the
existing approaches taken by the
community and I really want to emphasize
that existing approaches may not really
represent the best approaches one can
take so lots of research to be done uh
in in general are also from from certain
point of view uh if we we really go back
to machine learning theory certain
approaches being proposed here are also
not exactly right so one big issue we
are dealing with in training LMS is that
the theorical foundation usually cannot
connect very well with existing
practices so it's really I believe the
task of whole community to come together
to figure out how we can propose better
formulations but to connect what I
talked about before uh there generally
will be two uh stages in training this
agentic systems. The first stage we call
a super fun tuning or SFT.
So it is basically imitation learning. I
would like to imitate demonstration
trajectories that achieve correctness.
What that really means is that suppose
at the very beginning the IM doesn't
know anything. You give the IM a task it
output some garbage. uh that exactly was
a situation we talk about of the silly
attempts uh that cost lots of money and
resources we didn't make any progress in
that case usually to jump start a whole
system what you would do is that um you
would like to connect some demonstration
trajectories you say well there's a
particular query I would like to show
you as a human being uh the right set of
actions you need to take maybe access
this database also access another API
talk to another system final this whole
trajectory I just show you that what
about you try to replicate this next
time I ask you exactly the same question
what about you try to produce exact the
same answer as a demonstration I've just
shown to you so the hope is that I want
to minimize any silly or non meaningful
attempts the second stage is that well
maybe you are already entered the stage
where I give you a question uh sometimes
still make mistakes but it's not totally
wrong actually sometimes you are
reasonably correct. In this case, I
would like to let you explore because
the more you explore by yourself, uh the
better you learn in some sense very
similar to the philosophy of human
learning. Say in school if the professor
only gives us the precise answer to the
question say you just copy this. We are
not allowed to produce any homework to
be graded by the professor and we don't
get any feedback. Then maybe different
people who make mistakes in different
ways, right? I have this particular type
of mistake. I want to know it was wrong.
Nobody gave me that because professor
only give me the exact right answer.
This new question coming up. I have no
idea that I actually tend to make
certain type of mistakes. So the real
way to learn is to let model explore and
reinforce trajectories to achieve
correctness and discourage the ones that
do not. Going back to the previous
point, you actually also want the model
to produce very diverse trajectories so
that if you go wrong, I want to see you
go wrong. Then I tell you it goes wrong.
Instead of you say, well, essentially
everything is correct, but they are
always the same. Then you didn't really
learn too much about this. You want to
reinforce diverse great attempts from
the current model and discourage diverse
and bad attempts. both sides need need
to be diverse because diversity really
accelerates learning process.
So to uh really uh uh talk about the
details SFD stage and RL stage uh I
personally feel it's very intuitive
because it maps really well to human
being learning at SID stage is basically
maximize the likelihood of sampling the
demonstration trajectories and minimize
likelihood of sampling anything else
give you the predict trajectory say well
what about your samples hopefully it
really works very well it's just here so
that we can sample meaningful
trajectories. So one key aspect of SFT
is that demonstration samples needs to
be diverse. So basically if you give me
very few SF samples very similar style
then maybe what has happened is that the
model is not able to generate diverse
attempts later in AR stage which is bad.
And similarly for the uh uh second
requirements
uh uh here I wrote a requirement which
is ST should be light. uh the intuition
is also exactly same because if you have
conducted very heavy SFT which means
that you have basically tried to teach
the model for every question I collect
in a training set. I tell you what is
the right answer and I tell you please
remember this it is exactly only right
answer then later the model will lose
the ability to figure answers by its own
and in reality the real issue is that no
matter how big the collection of your
training data is it can never cover
every aspect of of our interaction with
and with humans. So if you really only
teach them to exactly follow your
demonstration answers uh generally it
would really fail for tasks that have
actually auto auto distribution.
So in the RL stage uh uh so here I'm
talking about the technical details you
can find the the details in essentially
every paper uh in RL in the ro stage I
want to sample very meaningful but very
different actions for the tasks the
environment and tools you have limited
compute you want to make sure you get as
diverse answers as possible as
meaningful as possible then you figure
out how correct each uh uh each action
sequence is how real and useful certain
actions are then you try to figure out
how to update your so that the next time
when you're trying to generate answers
you generate more the correct answers
you generate less the incorrect answers
uh that appears to be the hardest part.
So in some sense uh or what what's it's
also similar to what we observe in human
learning which is that when the
professor gives the students a task uh
then everyone submits the homework uh
the hardest thing is really to make sure
that the next time when there's a new
task coming up everyone is asked to
submit homework again uh how to make
sure that you really have produced a
better answer. So generally for human
beings people actually uh uh differ in
uh in this way. So many people by giving
the same feedback actually they produce
many different answers once given a new
set of tasks. That's exactly the same
situation for our algorithms. Use
different RO algorithms I give you same
amount of data then later turns out the
quality of the system actually is
different. summarize SAT just here to
discourage meaningless and lowquality
rollouts attempts and RL is here to
truly reinforce intelligence.
So I I indeed have prepared some more
slides talking about the details of RL
uh because I do believe that it's a very
critical research topic. The question is
that uh um has been a certain work uh
actually also work from coming from
Nvidia um talking about uh maybe uh
certain cases one can remove the SF
stage uh we conduct more RL uh by the
way it's also a trend demonstrated by
many frontier labs uh consume more
compute uh so that's actually also go
back goes back to one of the uh core uh
things I talk about when we are talking
about training algorithms is These days
it's really unclear what is actually the
correct training algorithm.
So because uh in some sense uh for those
of you who are very familiar with the
machine learning theory uh you know that
uh the current algorithmic formulation
for combination and RL they actually do
not align very well with machine
learning theory. If you started from a
theoretical perspective, work on
simplified models, you wouldn't be doing
this. You'll be doing something else and
on simplified models something else will
work so much better than this approaches
we currently take on. So that that's a
very big issue. So uh that's why we
believe that more exploration
in terms of different architecture,
different algorithms, better ways of
utilizing data both pre-training and
post- training data is very critical in
the community because currently it would
be very nice if we can move closer to
the theoretical principles while doing
something that's implementable in
practice. Uh this actually currently a
really important research topic. uh so
uh I I personally would encourage
everyone uh to really dive very deep
into this uh because uh uh I believe we
definitely have not converged uh in
terms of uh what's the right algorithm
to use uh as you'll be um you'll see
when I talk about later certain issues
related to the algorithms uh I by no
means mean that those are the maybe the
uh really right approaches we follow
that they will continue to be right even
10 years from now. But uh maybe the my
purpose is really to show you certain
observations people have made in the
past in running certain algorithms.
Hopefully it can motivate uh you to
design new algorithms that actually work
better. Uh uh maybe one perspective is
be considered as like pattern matching.
uh uh then you want to train the system
to be uh able to conduct critical
thinking and also be able to invent
something new. uh uh first of all uh my
feeling that uh it's uh it's generally
very difficult to understand what
exactly I am is doing because when you
really think about uh how do human
beings learn
uh in many cases suppose when we
actually trying to solve exam questions
right we are attending a class we are
also doing pattern matching
right in school professor shows us one
problem then he has answer then here's
the next problem very similar other we
also do doing very similar things. So uh
me personally I feel that it will be
fascinating to combine everything
related to human learning with I am
learning which is exactly what we are
trying to show here. So we have got some
good intuition with human learning. We
figure out how humans can learn better.
But the issue is that uh many humans
have no idea how they act learned
right they did something they got some
feedback next time they did something
else but here we need to write an
algorithm that's actually the hardest
thing we have no idea how to write an
algorithm and in terms of human learning
there are so many things we want to
learn and there are so many ways to
evaluate a person right just like these
days students take exams from all
courses right are we really sure all the
exams are really fair the develop person
the students in the right way it's super
interesting so uh one point I'm trying
to make here is that it's a so
fascinating area to think about that we
are actually absolutely at the infancy
of the area we really haven't figured
out what's the right way to train those
systems and also deploy them in certain
other critical applications but we have
made interesting observations which is
what I'm trying to show here hopefully
the observations are insight headful and
can stimulate some of the uh research
the people do uh uh people in in this
course can actually do in the future.
Okay. So uh now then let's dive slightly
uh deeper into reinforcement learning.
Uh I want to talk about three core
aspects. Uh I believe that we still need
to do a lot more research around those
aspects potentially new aspects but um
the community has made interesting
observations. I want to share the
observations here. One idea is to train
for longer. So one intuition you do you
situation you don't want to heat is that
you got some data sets you get to
attempt to solve the problems. You
attempt once or twice then later you
found that it can no longer attempt. So
every time it makes attempt produces
exactly the same answers saturates.
Okay. Not able to train longer. Not
ideal because for human beings we really
get constant feedback. We are given a
task, we propose a solution, we get that
uh feedback, next time we propose a
better solution. Ideally later we come
up with really amazing uh uh uh maybe
answers maybe inventing something really
new conducting cutting edge research
inventing general theory of relativity.
Right? It's a there's a very very high
bar here but it would not be very good
to say that it plateaus like very very
quickly. The second aspect observation
people have made is that uh somehow you
need to train on more difficult prompt
and tasks.
So intuitively also makes sense says as
for a human suppose you are given a task
to learn uh you only given really simple
tasks you already know how to solve it
really really well. you didn't really
learn anything new. That's uh for is
also exactly the same. But so we did
talk about some of the intricacy related
to this because if IM is only given
really difficult tasks like uh solving
REM hypothesis
um nobody can really solve and nobody
can make any progress. So that's
actually also a very big challenge.
Turns out it's important to convert the
intuition we have in human learning to
IM learning which is also very big
ongoing research project. I've been
talking about some observations people
have made. The third aspect I want to
emphasize is to train a more diverse
responses with high quality reward
feedback. So which is very natural as
for a human if you only interact with
very uh limited subjects. For example,
you only study
a single subject only take one course
and then you certainly would not be able
to uh answer the questions uh uh in
exams of other courses. Uh you need to
do that and so you need to see many
different meaningful answers per prompt
as uh as many u answers as possible. So
it re the good our algorithm should rely
on those pillars and they act even more
pillars in practice. So I'll very
briefly talk about those pillars. Uh one
pillar we talk about is train longer
being able to train longer. So there has
been many observations in the community
uh talking about this entropy mechanism
or entropy class collapse mechanism uh
and actually many different papers have
also very many other like correlated uh
metrics capturing something similar. But
the idea is the following. So on the
left I'm showing you a plot. X-axis is
the number of training steps. Basically,
you train longer and longer. Yaxis is
showing performance scheme. So,
basically how much the AM has actually
improved. So, uh and uh uh yeah, I'm
also it's is showing this uh uh uh yaxis
I have two curves. One is showing
performance gain, the other is showing
entropy left. By entropy I actually mean
that when I am is trying to generate it
next token uh as being uh uh uh
specified in literature as a
probabilistic inference because next
token is sampled from a distribution
right so by entropy I means that I
basically compute the entropy uh of the
token generation probability by large
entropy it means that there will be high
uncertainty in sampling the next token
then if we have a high entropy then very
likely if you sample the trajectory
twice you'll be able to get two very
very different trajectories. If the
entropy is very low, think of the
situation that whenever you are given a
prompt, then you ask model to predict
next token. Then the model is always
super sure uh next particular token uh a
certain token with 99% the probability.
Then even if you run this,
you sample it so many different times,
you wouldn't be able to sample many
different trajectories because uh only a
single trajectory uh has has very very
high probability. So what this plot has
shown that uh if you do not intervene if
you follow many different algorithms
what's going to happen that as the
number of steps increases
uh the performance would gain indeed you
see in terms of reward uh the model
started to produce very high quality
answers and started to uh to decrease.
So basically later only learns that I'm
able to only produce one one one answer.
So then we ask a question is it really
possible that we produce we still
produce really high quality answers but
at the same time do not achieve this
entropy collapse. So later answers all
correct still diverse being able to
explore uh but uh uh ideally for every
question I'm able to come up with five
different correct answers that's so
fascinating because uh uh even even for
a human it's actually very hard for a
very hard task come up with five
different correct answers.
So uh there has been some observations
in literature. Uh here I talk about uh
uh two approaches people have uh taken
uh in the literature uh to uh to
alleviate this issue. Uh on the left I'm
talking about uh this on policy versus
off policy issue. Okay. So basically uh
I'm I I increase number of training
steps. Now I observe that in terms of
training rewards which is the leftmost
figure uh I observe that for either on
policy or on policy algorithms and the
rewards actually increase uh in a
similar manner which means that uh uh I
do get better and better policies
um precisely by uh on policy I want to
emphasize that it's really exactly
emphas uh uh refers to the setting that
uh whenever I ask the reward model or a
verifier to judge the quality of the
attempts I only judge attempts produced
by the IM itself. So it is called on
policy which means that uh I do not try
to give you rewards or feedback based on
the answers produced by others or
produced by different weights. I really
want to give you feedback produced by
you at this point so that you can really
learn learn the best. So on policy
really means that I want you uh to learn
from your current mistakes not the
answers produced by other people
intuitively uh from the perspective of
human learning. If the answer is
produced by the students then we the
professor give the students very
detailed feedback the student can really
learn the most. But if the student
didn't write on the answer themselves,
copied from somewhere else, you give
feedback, maybe the student can still
try to learn but may not learn as well.
So that's actually intuition we are
trying to borrow here. Showing that if
you use some policy, the cha divergence
between the policy you train to our
original initial policy is small and
also the entropy still stays high. Uh
there's another uh uh yes so so
basically that's uh that is a very
detailed description showing that on
different benchmark
benchmarks that's like math 500 am 2425
on policy generally produces much better
answers. Uh there's a second approach uh
which we call uh balance the update
strength uh called adjusting the uh
clipping threshold or encouraging
exploration. So we're getting a very
technical here uh maybe I wouldn't be
spending too much time here. It is from
the paper double uh um which is specific
uh variants of a gpo uh the precise
formulation is given here. So
intuitively this RIT SATA is basically
the likelihood ratio we use in training.
Uh then generally to make JRPO stable we
need to add clipping to this likelihood
ratio. It's supposed to be fluctuating
around one. You clip at below one minus
epsilon low clip at above one plus
epsilon high. uh one important
observation made by the paper is that
you need to uh decouple those two
epsilons and make the epsilon high even
higher bigger than epsilon low. So
basically idea that you would like to
encourage the model to increase the
probabilities assigned to low
probability tokens. So the model is able
to explore very well. Um as you probably
can see here we are talking about lots
of hacks in the whole system. So uh
that's reason why I want to really
emphasize that different hacks may not
really represent the final state of arts
in particular many years later but I
hope the insight conveyed by the hacks
actually that you if this is uh
motivated by PO uh indeed PO also has
this clipping approach uh here the the
core observations that you actually
wanted to decouple this clipping
thresholds
so somehow indeed uh strikes some people
as as a hack does perform uh uh quite
well in particular uh based on the the
picture I show here uh with the clip
higher you see on the purple line
generally for the performance it's got
higher and in terms of generation
entropy is also it's also high doesn't
really collapse
okay uh another aspect people have
actually considered in the past in terms
of train longer is actually to add a
loss to encourage entropy directly
because we have been talking about uh
this entropy collapse issue when you
train longer the model only learns to
produce one answer is not ideal then
naturally you could also add a loss
function you say that what about I try
to maintain uh the entropy at certain
level and then there also lots of
different tricks in constructing a loss
make sure that the entropy is always
stays high for example you have a
certain entropy level you want to make
sure that the loss uh steers the uh
generation entropy to the particular
level of entropy uh there are many
things you can do uh still lots of
explor explorations um um that's
necessary but uh I hope that the
intuition is actually is clear
so precisely to encourage entropy
directly following this paper uh skywork
or open reasoner uh what they have done
is that they have a a particular like
entropy loss so the loss would actually
encourage you uh to increase entropy
along training so that entropy doesn't
really collapse and hopefully you also
achieve a higher test accuracy as being
shown on the picture on the left.
Okay, so that's uh one aspect of train
longer. Uh there's also another aspect
of uh train on more difficult prompts
and tasks. So uh in the same Andrew B
mechism paper actually along with many
different papers in the community uh
people have been thinking about how to
actually uh capture the aspects uh of u
um of separating the models performance
on hard prompts and on simpler prompts.
So they have a quite interesting plot
here. Uh so basically on the left uh
we'll be talking about what exactly we
are plotting in terms of coarience. So
uh the intuition is that I want to track
something which is related to the
correlation between the generation
likelihood of uh uh of the sequence with
the sequence uh quality uh or uh the
advantage. So basically I would like to
use this uh uh coarience uh between uh
log probability of the whole sequence to
the advantage we use in reinforce
learning. We're getting slightly
technical here but without looking at
too much details it's basically trying
to figure out whether uh I'm able to
align the confidence of generating
certain high quality answers with the
with the final performance. Ideally,
what's supposed to happen is that the
the model is supposed to be very
confident in generating the right
answers. It's supposed to be quite
uncertain in generating the wrong
answers. That would be fantastic because
next time I prompt the model, the model
is more likely to generate the right
answer because it's more confident. So
on the right, I'm showing a picture
basically listing the the training
curves of subsets of of data sets
corresponding to different levels of
accuracy. So basically one can see that
for the curves corresponding to very low
accuracy which is purple curve accuracy
0.1125
you see that this correlation uh uh
stays very low it really means that the
model is not able to very confidently
generate the right answers. So for the
model for the questions that's actually
very easy uh uh you'll be able to see
generally the collision is higher. So
that's actually also a important metric
we are trying to track. And on the left
uh I have another figure which is also a
very interesting observation made by
people in the past is really about how
you actually construct interesting
training sets. So what this one is is
been has been showing the following. So
I would like to train on multiple
different training sets. I'm I'm showing
a couple data sets double mass GSM8K
yours data yours difficult difficult is
more difficult data set and on the right
I'm basically checking the validation
accuracy on exactly the same validation
sets I'm trying to see by training on
different data sets act what is the the
final validation accuracy
um uh what's the pattern of a evolution
and the paper did observe something very
interesting for example uh GSM8K
actually refers to the the curve at the
very bottom. So what that process shows
that well when we are able to uh tren
this uh we we we found different u data
points corresponding to uh different
entropy uh one trend or clearly when
entropy is higher the final performance
is better which is uh which is a very
good trend but the second thing one
wants to see is that if you only train
on GSM 8K it really appears as your
final valid validation accuracy is low
in some sense it's really because GSM 8K
is too easy. You train these two easy
data sets, you shouldn't really expect a
model to behave very well on some very
challenging tasks. But another really
interesting observation you can make is
that here's a RL data and yours data
difficult. Then looking at the curve
actually the users IO data difficult
also uh is is below the curve of yours
IO data and your data contains the
difficult data set also contains
something that's actually not that
difficult. So somehow it also shows
something about the current learning
paradigm which is that you basically
blindly throw in super hard prompts. You
say that wow I really hope you're able
to learn. I give you very good feedback.
hopefully you'll be able to solve it.
Unfortunately, the IM itself or all the
existing algorithms are not smart enough
to really capture this. It didn't really
learn how to actually do very well. So,
somehow you need to somehow uh combine
very well uh uh different types of data
really make sure it can learn very well.
So, uh many different approaches have
been proposed in the past. Here I'm
talking about one approach proposed in
GRP lead paper which is very intuitive
still strikes some people as hacks but I
think the intuition is interesting uh
has many intuitions one intuition was
basically saying that uh well uh maybe
in order to provide a signal to themsel
prompt you got Right? Maybe I shouldn't
be rewarding rewarding you that much
because it's simple. You're supposed to
have already captured this and there are
many aspects captured by the paper. For
example, there's one answer you got this
question correct but unfortunately you
produced a answer that's too long. I
also would like to penalize you because
uh you're supposed to give a very simple
answer. The question isn't isn't that
hard. uh of course also if you give
something wrong I also give you really
negative answer really a negative
feedback. So many things we can do. So
in the paper it did show that it has
many different uh approaches uh to
actually adjust the corresponding
rewards. One can see that if you really
adjust the the weights for different
samples corresponding to advantage or
corresponding is difficulty then
performance gets improved. you
explicitly penalize a very long
generations many others then the quality
also becomes better so could really give
rise to lots of interesting ideas
uh
okay so that's on the uh on hardware
prompt side very clearly you can see
that's this problem is the open it's
really not clear in the community that
people have figured out the right
approach ultimate approach in solving
this uh there's one last aspect I want
to emphasize which is called sample
That also appears to be a very important
aspect of our algorithm. The whole idea
is that you should sample better so we
can train a more diverse responses with
high quality rewards. Goes back to the
original intuition. If you're not able
to sample lots of diverse queries uh uh
answers with with high quality
then then you'll be in trouble. So two
things I want to talk about on the left
I talk about so-called parallel
reasoning. Ideas could be very simple.
Oh, there are so many variants of this
approach. I'm talking about this paper
called ch select. Uh idea is that uh
well uh so I actually do have this slide
here. So basically uh when you uh
finally ask IM to produce answer you say
that what about you do not just directly
give me answer uh always give you a very
complex prompt on the right maybe ask
you to come up with like 32 different
answers right 32 different answers then
I give the prompt I say that what about
you basically uh select one of the
answers from the 32 then ideally here as
you can see from the answers uh
generally it's uh the final accuracy it
becomes so much better because uh uh the
really is given more time to figure out
uh the right answer is able to pick the
better one. Uh another one I want to
talk about is another recent paper
called promoting algorithm called deep
conf. U so that intuition is also about
uh improving uh majority voting. So uh
the point is that say uh without u this
quite sophisticate sampling method say
you want to sample like 32 times to
produce an answer you just give the same
prompt try 32 times get answer conduct
final majority voting but one potential
issue is that among the 32 times of
sampling maybe certain trajectories of
very low quality maybe you should just
know at very beginning or very early on
that trajectory is just Oh, if you knew
this, you're actually not supposed to
include that in a final majority voting.
You're supposed to only include those
trajectories that uh that's uh that's
actually likely uh to become part of the
right answer. So idea of deep conf is to
say that I would like to track the
generation confidence of these
trajectories for those trajectories with
very low generation confidence. I just
believe that model isn't even sure what
it's doing. when the model isn't even
sure what it's doing, I basically would
uh not include the model or assign a
very low weight in a final majority of
voting so that uh it should be able to
produce a better answer. So on the
right, I'm I'm showing some of the
results. For example, uh on the on the
same model GVD OSS120B,
if you use the deep conf compared to the
consensus, which is basically majority
voting, it actually improves uh because
indeed you are able to discard some of
the uh bad outputs of the model.
So uh that's essentially what I wanted
to talk about. Let me summarize uh the
the uh all the uh the content. Putting
everything together uh in the SFT data
you need to have very good expert
demonstrations. Uh RLI recipe you need
to focus on train longer, simple better,
train harder and ideally uh what
community uh is supposed to be doing is
really to solve everything as a whole.
You want to have a collection where we
curate environments, verifiers, skill up
intelligence. You need to figure out the
best definition what intelligence is.
You need to be able to to be able to
release algorithm to train longer harder
problems with diverse responses.
Uh you want to cross sources
uh community with all the community
efforts. You also want to make sure
analyze the strength and weaknesses of
benchmarks including in the collection.
Everyone can use it and also release
good algorithms for everybody to
experiment on. Uh it's going to be my
final final slide. uh hopefully after
today's lecture uh we have shared some
interesting observations we have made
but uh my real hope is that uh we have
stimulated your interest in this area
because one thing I really want to
emphasize is that this area is still
very immature lots of thing we really
haven't figured out and the general
perspective we have is that we really
want to bridge the gap between human
learning and system learning humans
engage in many different environments
focus on some lessons more than others.
We can explore ourselves or learn from
teachers. Uh we often evaluate the for
our intelligence on different tasks. How
do we exactly do that forms?
Uh in many cases really unclear. So uh
we really would like to encourage
economic efforts to join us uh in this
whole effort to collectively produce the
strongest agentic intelligence. Thank
you.